APPLICATION DEVELOPER II

Professional Summary

Highly-skilled software development professional bringing more than 20 years in software design, development and integration. Knowledgeable in data collection and analyzing techniques, graphical data interpretation and organizing and presenting business data. Add something really good as last sentence.

Skills

Work History

Application Developer II Gtech Services - Center Line, MI 06/2008 - 06/2013

- Sentinel (World tracking system) interface designer and programmer for large scale personal information data feeds to SecureIT server in Europe.
- Secure FTP.
- UTF8 bit with BOM.7x24 On-call support for Compliance department.
- Developed the architectural design from marketing requirement, an architectural model forprocessing server side XML directed from and
 processed on z/OS platform Wrote test and production OS/JCL, Procs, REXX and Easytrieve programs for the proof of concepton the
 z/OS mainframe. Extensive abend analysis.
- Formatted dump reading.
- HLASM abend analysis with Xpediter.
- CICS debugging with Intertest.
- Wrote REXX programs for transposition of fixed format data into variable format PC downloadablefiles to CA-7 for SQL server loads.

Application Developer Covance - Washington, DC 09/2007 - 12/2007

Developed and coded from specifications Enterprise COBOL, DB2v9 and VSAM batch programsunder z/OS. Wrote and installed their
production OS/JCL and Procs. Wrote in-stream Procs for on-request production runs. Documented coding Designed intermediate file
format for retail grocery store and UPC item level extracts. Wrote TSO/E REXX routine to provide an ad-hoc FTP interface for sending
Pathmark mainframedata to the A&P server for Oracle DB uploads. Easytrieve ad-hoc reporting SCLM change control.

Software Engineer Arconic - Pittsburgh, PA 10/2006 - 12/2006

 Coded and analyzed Korn Shell scripts and Micro Focus COBOL programs under HP/UX 11 forPharmacy Replenishment and Ordering (PRO) application. Completed documentation, coding and testing for Pharmacy Replenishment and Ordering (PRO) application. Wrote and implemented QA test frameworks with environment variable isolation with Perl/DBI.

Client/Server Programmer Arconic - Norcross, GA 10/2000 - 08/2001

- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software for Integrated.
- · Cashiering client/server systems.
- Wrote and implemented federal regulatory changes for Integrated Cashiering client/server systems.
- Wrote a major design change with a new mainframe rule including converting an existing DLL client rule.
- Coded and tested HPS Seer mainframe/PC client rules for Funds-In GUI changes with COBOL II, CICS, Transaction Bridging (DPL) and DB2 under OS/390 and z/OS for back-end processing.
- Debugging analysis of Datacom/DB data issues through CICS.

Web Developer Consultant Arconic - Bloomsburg, PA 06/2000 - 10/2000

JavaScript, HTML and XML code for web enabled claims processing under Sun/Solaris 5.6. Wrote and implemented data loading
processes using Perl/DBI with SQL for Oracle databases. Korn Shell scripting. Database loads using SQL*Loader. Secure Shell for remote
access and file transfers. Software IT Audit report. Duties included project team interviews, producing project level work flow analysis,
project lifecycle and internal audit documentation for Java based software managed by CVS under AIX 4.1.3.

Software Engineer Resource Date, Inc - Juneau , AK 03/2000 - 06/2000

- Developed, coded and implemented web page parsing algorithms for international stock market indexes using Perl/CGI, JavaScript and HTML under Sun/Solaris 5.6. Wrote uni-code dependant translation schemas using Perl/DBI with SQL for Oracle databases. Korn Shell scripting.
- Secure Shell for remote access and file transfers.

 $Software\ Engineer\ Alakaina\ Family\ Of\ Companies\ -\ Aberdeen\ Proving\ Ground\ ,\ MD\ 07/1999\ -\ 02/2000$

• Add back what you did with VAX and ORACLE.

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Resource Date, Inc - Anchorage, AK 02/1999 - 07/1999

Web Developer Resource Date, Inc - Portland, OR 11/1998 - 02/1999

- Sr. Programmer/Analyst Resource Date, Inc Houston, TX 06/1997 07/1998
- Sr. Programmer/Analyst Resource Date, Inc Boise, ID 04/1996 05/1997
- Sr. Programmer/Analyst Resource Date, Inc Juneau, AK 04/1995 08/1995

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Resource Date, Inc - Anchorage, AK 06/1992 - 09/1992

System Programmer Resource Date, Inc - Portland, OR 09/1990 - 01/1992

System Programmer Resource Date, Inc - Houston, TX 07/1990 - 10/1990

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Resource Date, Inc - Boise, ID 10/1989 - 05/1990

System Programmer Resource Date, Inc - Juneau, AK 03/1989 - 10/1989

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - Salt Lake City, UT 07/1988 - 01/1989

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - Colorado Springs, CO 03/1988 - 07/1988

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - Houston, TX 10/1987 - 03/1988

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - Fort Mill , SC 05/1987 - 10/1987

Sr. Programmer/Analyst Sammina Sci - Bothell , WA 10/1985 - 05/1987

Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - Silicon Valley, CA 03/1985 - 09/1985

Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - San Jose , CA 08/1984 - 03/1985

Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - Huntsville, AL 11/1983 - 08/1984

Programmer/Analyst Sanmina Sci - Fremont, CA 07/1983 - 11/1983

Programmer/Analyst Change Healthcare - Ambridge, PA 05/1983 - 07/1983

Programmer/Analyst PLAN INTL - City, STATE 10/1982 - 05/1983

System Programmer DATACOPI /ADP - City, STATE 05/1982 - 09/1982

Programmer/Analyst PACIFIC GAS & ELECTRIC - City, STATE 05/1981 - 05/1982

Programmer/Analyst FEDMART - City, STATE 03/1980 - 10/1980

Programmer/Analyst BRECK RESEARCH - City, STATE 02/1979 - 03/1980

System Programmer ADP, FLEMING FOODS - City, STATE

Software Engineer IV LAWRENCE LIVERMORE NATIONAL LABORATORY - City, STATE

Programmer/AnalystFB DATA SERVICES - FARM BUERU - City, STATE

Education

Associate of Arts : Computer Science Computer SciencePalomar College - City , State GPA: 3.00 Computer Science GPA: 3.00 FLMI - Level I - 2012 C# Programming Level 1 - Bellevue College 2012 : Skills

ad, AIX 4.1.3, architectural design, CA-7, Cashiering, CICS, client/server, COBOL II, COBOL, client, CVS, databases, Database, Datacom, DBI, Debugging, documentation, Easytrieve, FTP, Funds, GUI, HP/UX, HPS, HTML, DB2v, DB2, Intertest, Java, JavaScript, JCL, Korn Shell, mainframe, marketing, market, Micro Focus COBOL, access, C#, Enterprise, OS, ORACLE, Oracle DB, DB, OS/390, Perl, Perl/CGI, problem solving skills, processes, producing, coding, programmer, Programming, QA, reading, reporting, requirement, retail, REXX, scripting, Shell, scripting, Sun/Solaris 5.6, SQL server, SQL, translation, Troubleshooting, TSO/E, VAX, VSAM, web page, XML, Xpediter